Cameraperson is a documentary film directed by Kirsten Johnson.
As a visually radical memoir, CAMERAPERSON draws on the remarkable footage that filmmaker Kirsten Johnson has shot
and reframes it in ways that illuminate moments and situations that have personally affected her.
What emerges is an elegant meditation on the relationship between truth and the camera frame, as Johnson transforms scenes that have been presented
on Festival screens as one kind of truth into another kind of story—one about personal journey, craft, and direct human connection.
Self (archive footage), played by Kirsten Johnson.
Self (archive footage), played by Jacques Derrida.
Self (archive footage), played by Michael Moore.
Self (archive footage), played by Richard Johnson.
Cameraperson is a 2016 autobiographical collage documentary film.
The film is an account by director Kirsten Johnson about
her life and career as a cinematographer.
It relies on footage shot by Johnson across the
years in numerous different countries.
Cameraperson premiered at the Sundance Film Festival to critical
acclaim and won the top prize at the Sheffield Doc/Fest.